<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Arran's Life 🤓</title><description>Travel 🌏, Photography 📷 and Games 🕹️</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Arran's Life 🤓</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 2.25</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 19:22:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>The Outback Outline 🚐</title><description>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're traveling Australia in a pimped-out 98 Honda CR-V, roof top tent equipped and a custom kitchen in the boot. This excuse for a &amp;quot;4WD&amp;quot; will take a beating hauling ass across the land down under, with the stressed rear suspension screaming for help all 20,000 kilometers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/the-outback-outline/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5d0e74be8607f12e2529b385</guid><category>Travel</category><category>Australia</category><dc:creator>Arran Smith</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 10:45:10 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1523181887058-82fd90d1120c?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1523181887058-82fd90d1120c?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" alt="The Outback Outline 🚐"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're traveling Australia in a pimped-out 98 Honda CR-V, roof top tent equipped and a custom kitchen in the boot. This excuse for a &amp;quot;4WD&amp;quot; will take a beating hauling ass across the land down under, with the stressed rear suspension screaming for help all 20,000 kilometers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left Melbourne a week ago and we've been hooning north since, we're headed up past Sydney to a Bed and Breakfast to WWOF for a bit then we're doing a full anti-clockwise rotation around Australia with only a handful of mechanical breakdowns planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to be writing every couple of days about what's been going on, if I stop you can safely assume I'm being digested by a snake, shark or crocodile - Either that or I'm getting lazy, I'll let you be the judge of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've got any recommendations on places to visit, leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.3</title><description>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had successfully escaped Ho Chi Minh City, we had begun our adventure to &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/vTE4PYxH9SA2"&gt;Phan Thiet&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riding out of the city and into the country was a fascinating experience, being the first time I had seen anything like this I was in awe - Farmers working the rice fields, people&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/nam-pt3/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5d0e74be8607f12e2529b384</guid><category>Vietnam</category><category>Travel</category><dc:creator>Arran Smith</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 04:19:42 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1454579943364-13b2d508c27a?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1454579943364-13b2d508c27a?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" alt="Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had successfully escaped Ho Chi Minh City, we had begun our adventure to &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/vTE4PYxH9SA2"&gt;Phan Thiet&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riding out of the city and into the country was a fascinating experience, being the first time I had seen anything like this I was in awe - Farmers working the rice fields, people herding their cattle and endless runs of markets kept me amused for the long trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had made good distance but we we're still an hour away from &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/vTE4PYxH9SA2"&gt;Phan Thiet&lt;/a&gt; when the weather changed it's tune. We pulled over, put on our rain jackets and after much discussion we decided to battle the all-mighty rain and push onward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the weather fought back, flooding the roads, soaking our boots and rendering us blind with the constant downpour on our visors. After 20 minutes of a brave but stupid battle we sought shelter from the tremendous storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We parked underneath what looked like an abandoned gas station with a couple of Vietnamese ladies hanging out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Nhà Nghỉ, Nhà Nghỉ?&amp;quot; (Guest House)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the ladies shot up, jumped on her motorbike and gestured us to follow to which we happily complied. After following her down a few muddy (previously dirt) roads we arrived at a deserted beach resort. Thank you unknown Vietnamese lady!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning we stumbled out of our room to see the owners had prepared breakfast for the entire resort (just us). We tucked in to what looked like shrimp, crab and other seafood dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We resumed our journey to &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/vTE4PYxH9SA2"&gt;Phan Thiet&lt;/a&gt; by passing a little village called &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/eEvTwSiXzBn"&gt;La Gi&lt;/a&gt;, this was to avoid a little bit of the notorious &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Route_1A_(Vietnam)"&gt;1A Highway&lt;/a&gt;. The drive turned out to be a beautiful sea-side cruise where all the local kids were stoked with our presence, excitedly waving as we went past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thesecondcrash"&gt;The Second Crash&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we drove on the road became more rugged, increasing the already difficult drive. I was at the front of the pack when I saw a decent mound of dirt approaching, I was slowing down to ride over the bump when suddenly Luke bumped into my right side. I turn around to see his bike wobble for a couple of meters and finally topple over, sending his face into the dirt! He went out cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lewis and I rushed over, pulled the bike from his tangled legs and let him slowly come to. We were in the middle of no-where, yet strangely enough a Vietnamese man wandered out of the bush and make sure we were okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/10/20161018_130216.jpg" alt="Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all having a laugh and a drink we assessed the damage to Luke's bike, It was in pretty rough shape. We got out the spray paint and appropriately painted &amp;quot;RIP&amp;quot; on the tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/10/IMG_0323.JPG" alt="Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the steering off-center, foot pedals bent and the battery barely hanging on, we set off for a mechanic. We stopped at the first &amp;quot;xe máy&amp;quot; (Motorbike) sign and got everything fixed for a couple of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="meetingbong"&gt;Meeting Bong&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually we made it to &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/vTE4PYxH9SA2"&gt;Phan Thiet&lt;/a&gt;, Luke had decided that Vietnam and it's crazy roads was too much and wanted to go home; This is how we met Bong!&lt;br&gt;
Luke sold his motorbike for 2.5M VND ($110 USD) to the keen mechanic and Lewis and I both got our brake pads replaced and chains oiled. Bong then suggested we all go for a drink by way of a drinking gesture, we hopped on our bikes and apprehensively followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived and he invited us inside his home, I was a little worried about entering a strange mans house in a small Vietnamese town from the back of a dimly lit alley..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was great! Bong soon unloaded a box of beer on the dining table and we soon settled in. His wife brought out the best fried chicken I have &lt;strong&gt;ever&lt;/strong&gt; had, Bong scrunched up his face when I offered him some; He preferred his chewy dried fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bong's parents even came by for the impromptu party! We had more beer, learned some Vietnamese and laughed. Bong called Luke a taxi to Ho Chi Minh for his flight out the next day, Lewis and I headed to a guest house and called it a night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an incredible experience I will never forget, Cheers Bong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/10/20161018_174710.jpg" alt="Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.2</title><description>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had bought a bike, but there was only one small problem.. The engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, I should of listened to the two very persistent Vietnamese gentlemen when I was viewing the bike. They repeatedly pointed to the engine and shook their heads, even going as far as&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/nam-pt2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5d0e74be8607f12e2529b37e</guid><category>Vietnam</category><category>Travel</category><dc:creator>Arran Smith</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 01:34:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1506741485568-47c278a3e70a?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1506741485568-47c278a3e70a?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" alt="Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.2"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had bought a bike, but there was only one small problem.. The engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, I should of listened to the two very persistent Vietnamese gentlemen when I was viewing the bike. They repeatedly pointed to the engine and shook their heads, even going as far as showing my an image of a head gasket. As with many Vietnamese merchants, I thought they were attempting to scam me.. they weren't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I met Vihn - an absolute champion of a mechanic. I left my bike with him and he gave me a scooter to borrow in the interim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that day, I was eating dinner at The Crazy Dutch when I overheard two British guys talking about a motorbike trip to Hanoi. So naturally I joined in and asked about their plans - Lewis and Luke told me they we're considering the trip but they didn't know how to ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What better place to learn how to ride a motorbike than Ho Chi Minh City.. Right?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After convincing them I would teach them how to ride manual, we decided to join forces and tackle Vietnam together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took them to Vihn's house, Luke and Lewis each bought their own shitty bike. I had also negotiated a cheaper repair for my bike since I brought Vihn business, so that worked well for me too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/10/20161016_175840--1-.jpg" alt="Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id="hittingtheroadliterally"&gt;Hitting the road. (Literally)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke at 4.30AM to avoid peak traffic - We packed our gear, stockpiled water and filled our bikes with premium Vietnamese fuel. With only 18 kilometers of a corrugated iron jungle between us and the open road, we set off on the adventure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first, a &lt;strong&gt;crash&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being the most experienced rider, I rode behind the pack and arguably got the best view for the event about to unfold. Just picture this with me - This intersection had 4 streets, 8 Lanes each. Each red light was littered with hundreds of motorbikes anxiously waiting for the green; we sat at the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lights Change. Everything is normal, we're in the middle of the intersection until I hear Luke's engine roaring! He's got the clutch engaged, the bike is revving like mad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Don't let the clutch go, Don't let the clutch go, Don't let the clutch go!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He drops the clutch like a hot oven tray, the bike fucking soars into the air doing a half a back flip and slams Luke into the tarmac!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stop my bike in front of his, shielding him from the stampede of traffic whizzing past us, I make sure he's dandy and we pull our bikes to the side of the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tis but a scratch. I kick his bent foot pedals back into an acceptable shape, we take a breath and continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; crash we experienced in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/nam-pt3"&gt;Click Here for Part 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.1</title><description>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hadn't really traveled overseas, I wanted to do something outrageous for my first trip, something really strange. I decided to ride a &lt;em&gt;deathtrap&lt;/em&gt; from Ho Chi Minh City to Hanoi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What started as a joke between me and my parents, soon developed into an obsession. I was reading articles&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/nam-pt1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5d0e74be8607f12e2529b37c</guid><category>Vietnam</category><category>Travel</category><dc:creator>Arran Smith</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 10:24:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1490352337072-58b1e4fe4578?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1490352337072-58b1e4fe4578?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" alt="Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.1"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hadn't really traveled overseas, I wanted to do something outrageous for my first trip, something really strange. I decided to ride a &lt;em&gt;deathtrap&lt;/em&gt; from Ho Chi Minh City to Hanoi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What started as a joke between me and my parents, soon developed into an obsession. I was reading articles about similar trips, watching YouTube videos, browsing forums and remaining purposefully ignorant to the  countless posts condemning such trips as &amp;quot;death wishes&amp;quot;. After a couple weeks It was no longer a joke, I was convinced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Oh Dad, by the way I'm going to motorbike across Vietnam in a couple of months&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple of months, and I was jet lagged wandering around Kuala Lumpur, waiting for my connecting flight to Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had spent the day meandering though humming markets and filthy streets, stopping to chat with the welcoming locals. &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Are you living for eating, or eating for living?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; a local man inquired, to which I did not have an answer to.. I still don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id="thehochiminhhunt"&gt;The Ho Chi Minh Hunt&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arriving in Ho Chi Minh City was an overload of the senses; the pungent smell, the sweltering heat, streets bursting full of people and the general chaos that surrounded me. With a population of 8.426 million, a whopping near &lt;em&gt;double&lt;/em&gt; of New Zealand's it's no wonder I was overwhelmed. I was quick to adjust as I had a mission, I had to find a motorbike!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="findingabike"&gt;Finding A Bike&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There a few ways you could find a motorbike in Ho Chi Minh, local dealers, hostel noticeboards, Facebook groups and Craigslist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prices of bikes range from $150USD to $350USD depending on the condition and accessories included, Such as Bag Racks, Canvas Covers, Phone Mounts, Chargers and Helmets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking for a bargain; I was scouring Craiglist when I found a 110cc Honda Win priced at $220USD. Chris, the guy selling the bike met me at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/yhUuLR2Juov"&gt;The Crazy Dutch Hostel&lt;/a&gt;, The bike was rough as guts, spitting smoke and a had shoddy paint job. But since it was Army Green, I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought that wonderful piece of shit for 4 Million VND ($175USD)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/09/IMG_20161015_173926.jpg" alt="Motorbiking Vietnam Pt.1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/nam-pt2"&gt;Click Here for Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Vietnam Preperation</title><description>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;p&gt;For an overseas trip, preparation is key. When packing don't forget the essentials such as a first aid kit, copies of important documents and a Forrest Gump hat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a list of everything I took to Vietnam for my trip.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/nam-pt1"&gt;Click Here for Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Electronics:
    • Radio
    • Headphones
    • Torch x&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/nam-prep/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5d0e74be8607f12e2529b37d</guid><category>Vietnam</category><category>Travel</category><dc:creator>Arran Smith</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 02:49:35 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1503956011720-b85f3dcf88ce?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1503956011720-b85f3dcf88ce?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" alt="Vietnam Preperation"&gt;&lt;p&gt;For an overseas trip, preparation is key. When packing don't forget the essentials such as a first aid kit, copies of important documents and a Forrest Gump hat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a list of everything I took to Vietnam for my trip.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/nam-pt1"&gt;Click Here for Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Electronics:
    • Radio
    • Headphones
    • Torch x 2
    • Samsung S6 Smartphone 32GB 
    • Micro USB Charger 2.4A
    • UE BOOM 2 Wireless Speaker
    
    • Camera
        ○ Nikon D5200 Body
        ○ 50mm Prime Lens
        ○ 55 - 300mm Tele Lens
        ○ 10 - 20mm Wide Lens
        ○ Charger Car / Plug
        ○ USB SD Card Reader
        ○ OTG Adapter (Micro to USB)
        ○ Extra Lens Cap
        ○ 3 SD Cards ( 8GB x 2 , 32GB x 1 )
        ○ Lens Cleaning Solution
        ○ Manfrotto Tripod
        ○ Neutral Density Filters
        
Clothes:
    • Underwear x 12
    • Socks x 8
    • T-Shirts x 4
    • Singlets x 3
    • Shorts x 2
    • Pants x 3
    • Wool Sweater (Army Green)
    • Cotton / Poly Hoodie
    • Gorka Jacket
    • Hats
        ○ Forest Gump Hat
        ○ Camo Hat
        ○ Thrasher Beanie
    • Hiking Boots
    • Running Shoes
    
Misc:
    • Kathmandu Portable Seat
    • First Aid Kit
    • Travel Medication
    • Home-Made Phone Charger for Motorbike
    • Sleeping Bag
    • Zip Ties
    • Pens
    • Paper
    • Hacky Sack
    
    • 3 x Copies of Entry Visa,
    • Flight Information
    • Copy of Passport and License
    • International Drivers License
    • Trip Outline and Information (To be keep inside bag)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to take my full camera set up with me. The problem was I knew traveling with a tramping bag, a backpack and a camera bag would be far too cumbersome for a motorbike, so I had to think of a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a thick piece of foam, stenciled an outline of camera and cut it out to make a snug fit for each lens and the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I whacked that in my backpack and I had a dual purpose backpack / camera bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/09/CamDIYBag.png" alt="Vietnam Preperation"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>1 Game, 1 Week</title><description>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;p&gt;One day while having the daily dose of cereal I had an idea, a procedurally generated open world massively multiplayer online survival game with RPG elements, realistic physics simulations and steering wheel support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead I decided to tackle a greater challenge, Crowd Pleaser..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After participating in Ludum Dare 38 and&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/1-game-1-week/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5d0e74be8607f12e2529b379</guid><category>Development</category><dc:creator>Arran Smith</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 05:57:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1530328411047-7063dbd29029?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1530328411047-7063dbd29029?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" alt="1 Game, 1 Week"&gt;&lt;p&gt;One day while having the daily dose of cereal I had an idea, a procedurally generated open world massively multiplayer online survival game with RPG elements, realistic physics simulations and steering wheel support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead I decided to tackle a greater challenge, Crowd Pleaser..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After participating in Ludum Dare 38 and creating &lt;a href="https://azza292.itch.io/roos-small-world"&gt;Roo's World&lt;/a&gt; in 48 hours, I was convinced I could design, draw and polish a simple Android game in 5 days, so that's what I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was as simple as you could ask, a tap to jump reaction based game with increasing difficulty over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to work immediately after breakfast, sitting down and creating a 2D array of objects, adding a simple sprite and looping through them to create the &lt;em&gt;wave&lt;/em&gt; effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used a free pixel animator called &lt;a href="http://www.piskelapp.com/"&gt;Piskel&lt;/a&gt; to create my animated sprites. I then used a palette swapping technique to generate a more visually appealing crowd while saving a ton of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I added a wave selector that randomly triggered waves from each direction, A player character and made the rest of the art assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then after getting the game play right, adding high scores and achievements I was done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/09/Pn1MkR.png" alt="1 Game, 1 Week"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I really enjoyed the process, I learnt a few useful techniques and I would recommended to every beginner game dev to put down that enormous project for one week and finish something small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UI was supplied from every Game Developers best-friend, Kenney. &lt;a href="https://kenney.nl/assets/ui-pack"&gt;UI Pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fantastic music was composed by &lt;a href="https://wyver9.bandcamp.com/"&gt;Wyver9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tap the screen and join a Mexican wave hurdling across your screen, then do that again, and a few more times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ArranSmith.CrowdPleaser&amp;pcampaignid=MKT-Other-global-all-co-prtnr-py-PartBadge-Mar2515-1"&gt;&lt;img alt="1 Game, 1 Week" src="https://play.google.com/intl/en_us/badges/images/generic/en_badge_web_generic.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>